Thomas Lowe Hughes Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Personal File, 1918-2017 (Box 186-200)
  - Carleton College, Northfield, Minn. (Box 188)
    - Student Federalists (Box 192)
      - Conferences and meetings, 1943-1948, (2 folders) (Box 192)
      - Correspondence (photocopies), 1943-1947, (2 folders) (Box 192)
      - Correspondence (notes about), undated, (2 folders) (Box 192)
      - Jonas, Gilbert, One Shining Moment: A Short History of the American Student World Federalist Movement, 1942-1953, 1998-2001 (Box 192)
      - Oral history, 2007 (Box 193)
      - Schwartz, Gene, anthology, 2000-2003 (Box 193)
    - United Nations Conference, San Francisco, Calif., 1945 (Box 193)
  - Clippings about Hughes, 1961-1990 (Box 193)
  - Diaries, 1933, 1936, 1940-1942, (2 folders) (Box 193)
  - Diaries (photocopies and notes about), 1940-1960 See also Container 8, Diary, entries related to Bowles; Container 12, Diary, entries related to Humphrey, 1945-1960 (Box 193)
  - Diaries (photocopies and notes about), 1940-1960 See also Container 8, Diary, entries related to Bowles; Container 12, Diary, entries related to Humphrey, 1945-1960 (Box 194)
  - Israel (Box 194)
    - Clippings, 1950 (Box 194)
    - Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 194)
    - Notes, 1950, circa 2002 (Box 194)
    - Printed and reference material, 1949-1950 (Box 194)
    - Zionist Newsletter, 1949-1950 (Box 194)
  - Mankato, Minn. (Box 194)
    - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 194)
    - Hohenzollern family, 1918, 1938-1941, 2017 (Box 194)
    - National Forensic League, 1942-1943, (3 folders) (Box 194)
    - National Forensic League, 1942-1943 (Box 195)
    - Poem, 1929 (Box 195)
    - Richard, John, correspondence, 1937-1947 (Box 195)
    - Stevenson, Adlai E., campaign, 1952 (Box 195)
  - Scott, James, interview, 2015 (Box 195)
  - Smith, Bruce, biography notes, 2016-2017, (2 folders) (Box 195)
  - University of Oxford (Box 195)
    - Argyll, Scotland, 1948 (Box 195)
    - Correspondence (Box 195)
      - Beytien, Jay, 1948-1949 (Box 195)
      - Bryn-Jones, David, 1947-1949 (Box 195)
      - Hughes family, 1947-1948, (2 folders) (Box 195)
      - Larson, Ruth, 1947-1949 (Box 196)
    - Devon, England, 1948-1949 (Box 196)
    - England (general), 1947-1948 (Box 196)
    - General, 1947-1948 (Box 196)
    - Germany, 1948 (Box 196)
    - Germany and Netherlands, 1950 (Box 196)
    - Hilary term, 1948-1949, (2 folders) (Box 196)
    - Italy, 1948, (2 folders) (Box 196)
    - Labour Party pamphlets, 1945-1949 (Box 196)
    - Lindgren, Emmy Lou, "Labour Party Foreign Policy," 1947 (Box 197)
    - Michaelmas term, 1947-1948, (3 folders) (Box 197)
    - Paris, France, 1948 (Box 197)
    - Politics, 1947-1948 (Box 197)
    - Queen Elizabeth (ship) trip, 1947 (Box 197)
    - Rhodes Scholarship, 1946-1947 (Box 197)
    - Second chambers notes, 1948 (Box 197)
    - Social clubs, 1947-1949 (Box 198)
    - Summer travel, 1949 (Box 198)
    - Switzerland and Austria, 1947-1948 (Box 198)
    - Trinity term, 1948-1949, (2 folders) (Box 198)
    - Wales, 1948 (Box 198)
    - World Movement for World Federal Government Conference, Luxembourg, 1948 (Box 198)
    - Writings and columns, 1947-1948 (Box 198)
  - Yale Law School (Box 198)
    - Correspondence, 1949, (2 folders) (Box 198)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1952, (7 folders) (Box 199)
    - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 200)
    - Yale Political Journal, 1947 (Box 200)
  - Washington, D.C., correspondence, 1951, 1955 See also Container 14, Senate Subcommittee on Labor and Labor-Management Relations (Box 200)
- National Security Classified Information, 1961-1970 (Box CL 1-CL 5)
  Material types include correspondence, memoranda, notes, and briefings primarily from Thomas Hughes’ tenure at the Department of State.
  Listed and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were separated. Items marked Top Secret and Sensitive Compartmented Information are housed separately from other classified material in this series.
  - United States Congress
    - Bowles, Chester
      - Correspondence, chronological, 1964 (Container 1) (Box CL 1)
      - Correspondence, chronological, 1965-1969 (Container 2), (2 folders) (Box CL 1)
      - Correspondence, India, 1967 (Container 2) (Box CL 1)
      - General, 1961, 1968 (Container 6) (Box CL 1)
      - India, 1967 (Container 7) (Box CL 1)
      - Undersecretary of state, office file, 1961 (Container 9) (Box CL 1)
    - Humphrey, Hubert H.
      - General, 1969 (Container 13) (Box CL 1)
      - Notes on Humphrey, 1965 (Container 14) (Box CL 1)
      - Speeches, drafts, 1964 (Container 14) (Box CL 1)
  - Department of State
    - Bureau of Intelligence and Research (INR)
      - Appointment to INR, 1961 (Container 15) (Box CL 1)
      - Appointments, 1968-1969 (Container 16), 1966-1969 (Box CL 1)
      - Bowles, Chester, 1962 (Container 16) (Box CL 1)
      - Bowles, Chester, 1962 (Container 16) (Box TS 1)
      - Chronological file, 1964-1969 (Containers 16 and 17), (6 folders) (Box CL 1)
      - Cuban Missile Crisis briefing, autographs of attendees and miscellaneous, 1962 (Container 17) (Box TS 1)
      - Culebra Island, 1970 (Container 18) (Box CL 1)
      - George C. Denney file, chronological file, 1963-1966 (Containers 18 and 19), (12 folders) (Box CL 1)
      - George C. Denney file, chronological file, 1967-1974 (Containers 20, 21, and 22), (12 folders) (Box CL 2)
      - George C. Denney file, chronological file, 1963-1967 (Containers 19 and 20), (3 folders) (Box TS 1)
      - Helms, Richard, 1969 (Container 23) (Box CL 2)
      - Hilsman, Roger, 1967 (Container 23) (Box CL 2)
      - Kennedy, Robert, 1964 (Container 23) (Box CL 2)
      - Memoranda, INR, 1966 (Container 23) (Box CL 2)
      - Notes
        - Assistant secretary's meeting, 1963, 1965 (Container 24), (2 folders) (Box CL 2)
        - Latin American political climate, 1963 (Container 24) (Box CL 2)
        - Miscellaneous, 1963 (Containers 24 and 25) (Box CL 2)
        - "S" and "U" staff meetings, 1968-1969 (Container 25) (Box CL 2)
        - Secretary's policy planning committee, 1963 (Container 25) (Box CL 2)
      - Parties, 1963-1969 (Container 26) (Box CL 2)
      - Parties, personal and INR, 1968 (Container 26) (Box CL 2)
      - Study group, Hans Speier on Germany, 1965 (Container 28) (Box CL 2)
      - Travel
        - Brussels, Belgium and Paris, France, 1962 (Container 28) (Box CL 2)
        - India and Pakistan, General, 1964 (Container 30) (Box CL 2)
      - Under secretary's office, 1961 (Container 31) (Box CL 3)
      - United States Intelligence Board notes, 1961-1967 (Container 31), (6 folders) (Box CL 3)
      - United States Intelligence Board notes, 1961-1967 (Container 31) (Box TS 1)
      - United States Intelligence Board notes, 1963 (Container 31) (Box SCI 1)
      - Vietnam, 1963-1970 (Containers 31 and 32), (5 folders) (Box CL 3)
    - United States Embassy, London, England
      - Appointments, 1969-1970 (Container 32) (Box CL 3)
      - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Container 33) (Box CL 3)
      - Southeast Asia, 1970 (Container 35 and 36) (Box CL 3)